

Muhammad Nouman Khan

Website: https://github.com/iammuhammadnoumankhan

○ WhatsApp Messenger: +923139520997

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-nouman-khan-248530233

Gender: Male **Date of birth:** 20/06/2004 **Nationality:** Pakistani

ABOUT ME

I'm an Al engineer with 2 years of experience in Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Computer Vision projects. Currently focusing on Language Models, I'm adaptable to new technologies and actively involved in research projects. Pursuing a BS in AI from Pak-Austria Fachhochschule.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[10/10/2023 - 11/04/2024] **Database development engineer**

Canada Tax & Financial Services

City: Edmonton | Country: Canada

- Database Management
- Automation
- Chatbot Creation

[28/08/2023 - 28/09/2023]

Summer Intern

Rapidev

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan

ML/Computer Vision Intern

- Data Annotation utilizing CVAT and Roboflow
- Managing GIS and raster data
- Crafting APIs for raster-to-vector conversion
- Model for Car number plate detection

[18/07/2022 - 25/09/2022] **Internship**

SPCAI - PAF-IAST

City: Haripur | **Country:** Pakistan Machine Learning on Edge Devices

- Learn Python | Machine Learning & Deep Learning | Version Control | tflite
- Worked on OAK-D | Raspberry Pi
- Projects: Facial Attendance Management System | Solar Ir-radiance Forecasting

EDUCATION AND TRAIN-ING

Bachelor of Applied Science and Information Technology, Artificial

[27/09/2021 – Current] Intelligence

Pak Austria Fachhochschule https://paf-iast.edu.pk/

Address: Khanpur road, Mang, 22620, Haripur, Pakistan

[05/08/2019 - 20/09/2021] **Intermediate**

Pakistan Scouts Cadet College Batrasi https://www.pscc.edu.pk/

Address: Atarsheehsa, balakot road, 21300, Mansehra, Pakistan

[05/05/2017 - 27/06/2019] Matric

Aurakzai Model School https://www.facebook.com/amsac.official/

Address: Hazara University,, 21300, Mansehra, Pakistan

PROJECTS

Facial Attendance Management System

Solar Irradiance Forecasting

Fine Tune Whisper on Quranic Data (HuggingFace)

Link: https://huggingface.co/iammuhammadnoumankhan/whisper-small-ar

Car Number Plate detection (YOLO)

Chatbot for Tax & Finance Services (Openai, Langchain)

Data Scrapers (Selenium, BS4)

Attention based Glaucoma Detection

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Knowledge:

Data Science, Machine Learning, Deep, NLP & CV, LLMs, GPT

Languages:

Python, Matlab, HTML, CSS, Web development, SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB

Frameworks:

Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras, Langchain, Crew Al, Django, Flask, Fast API

Cloud:

GCP Cloud Run, Amazon Sage Maker(AWS), Heroku

Libraries:

Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Spacy, NLTK, Opency, Matplotlib / Seaborn, scipy, Transformers, BeautifulSoup, Selenium

Tools:

Jupyter, docker, GitHub, Git, Google DataStudio, Gradio, Streamlit, Vscode, Kafka

Others:

Statistics & Probability, Calculus, Mathematics, Linear Algebra, Worked on Complex Datasets, Big data, Statistical Analysis, Data Mining, Model Building and Deploying, Hypothesis Testing, Data Analytics, Model Fine-tuning

CERTIFICATES & COURSES

Machine Learning Specilization (Deeplearning.ai)

Generative AI with Large Language Models (Deeplearning.ai)

SOFT SKILLS

Skills

- Analytical Thinking
- Problem-Solving
- Collaboration
- Communication
- Continuous Learning
- Adaptability
- Time Management

Spoken Languages

- English
- Urdu

PROJECTS EXHIBITION

[12/02/2023 – 12/02/2023] **Uraan Projects Exhibition(2023)**

I secured the 4th position in the Uraan Project Exhibition on February 12, 2023, at Pak Austria Fachhochschule.

My Project was about "SOLAR IRRADIANCE FORECASTING".

Link: https://www.instagram.com/p/CojswxOgUDm/?igshid=MzRIODBiNWFIZA==

[07/07/2023 - 07/07/2023] **Uraan Projects Exhibition (SPRING - 2023)**

I secured the first position in the Uraan Project Exhibition on July 7, 2023, at Pak Austria Fachhochschule.

My project in the DJANGO FRAMEWORK was titled "WEB SITE WITH DIFFERENT AI MODELS DEPLOYED."

Link: https://www.linkedin.com/posts/muhammad-nouman-khan-248530233 aipython-technology-activity-7083500779998765056-FS8Z? utm source=share&utm medium=member android